teluguodu.com 2018-12-20

# Privacy Policy | Teluguodu

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in **Information Technology Act 2000 and Information Technology Rules 2011 adopted by India’s IT Ministry** , is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**  
When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**  
We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or enter information on our site.

Provide us with feedback on our products or services When Sends a Message.

**How do we use your information?**  
We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * To follow up with them after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)

**How do we protect your information?**  
We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.  
We only provide articles and information. We never ask for credit card numbers.  
We do not use Malware Scanning.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**  
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.

**•**  Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer

better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly. It won’t affect the user’s experience that make your site experience more efficient and may not function properly.

**Third-party disclosure**  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

**Third-party links**  
We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website.

**We have implemented the following:**  
We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) we use them for traffic/visitors analysis only.

**Opting out:**  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser add on.

**Information Technology Act 2000 and Information Technology Rules 2011 adopted by India’s IT Ministry**

The Information Technology (Amendment) Act, 2008 made significant changes to the Information Technology Act, 2000, introducing Section 43A. This section provides compensation in the case where a body corporate that possesses, deals or handles any sensitive personal data or information in a computer resource that it owns, controls or operates, is negligent in implementing and maintaining reasonable security practices and procedures and thereby causes wrongful loss or wrongful gain to any person.

In 2011, the Government of India prescribed the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 by publishing it in the Official Gazette. These rules require a body corporate to provide a privacy policy for handling of or dealing in personal information including sensitive personal data or information.

**Such a privacy policy should consist of the following information in accordance with the rules:**  
Clear and easily accessible statements of its practices and policies;

  * Type of personal or sensitive personal data or information collected;
  * Purpose of collection and usage of such information;
  * Disclosure of information including sensitive personal data or information;
  * Reasonable security practices and procedures..

Visitors or users cannot change your personal information: Once it is submitted to us from our contact us page.

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**  
We do not honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**  
It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking except Google and Alexa.

**India and the Spam Menace:**  
Spam legislation is non-existent in India. The much-touted Information Technology Act of 2000 does not discuss the issue of spamming at all. It only refers to punishment meted out to a person, who after having secured access to any electronic material without the consent of the person concerned, discloses such electronic material to any other person. It does not have any bearing on violation of individual’s privacy in Cyberspace. The illegality of spamming is not considered.

The IT Act 2000 in India prohibits malicious communication through electronic means.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information; respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questionsIf at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at
  * Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from  **ALL**  correspondence.

**To be in accordance with India** **IT Act 2000, we agree to the following:**

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

**Contacting Us**  
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

Email: [info@teluguodu.com](mailto:info@teluguodu.com)

**Updates to this policy:**  
This Privacy Policy was last updated on 2017-11-23. From time to time we may change our privacy practices. We may or may not notify you of any material changes to this policy, please check our site periodically for updates **.**

**Jurisdiction:**  
If you choose to visit the website, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and the website’s terms of use. In addition to the foregoing, any disputes arising under this Policy shall be governed by the laws of India.
